Guide to the Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Gertrude Stein, 1894-1947; Series I; 39; (94 boxes)
  - GERTRUDE STEIN BIBLIOGRAPH
    - Jokes for Jessie
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, n.d.
        In: Attacks
      - Typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 631)
    - Jonas Julian Caesar and Samuel
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1923] (Box 30, Folder 632)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, corrected, 1923 (Box 30, Folder 633)
    - Julia Marlowe
      - Holograph manuscript, [1908-12] (Box 30, Folder 634)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copies (2 versions), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 635)
    - Kicking
      - Holograph manuscript, [1919] (Box 30, Folder 636)
        Also contains: Develop Spanish
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, n.d.
        In: Old dogs
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 637)
    - A Kind of women
      - Manuscript notebook, [1908-12] (Box 30, Folder 638)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 639)
    - The King or something. A play
      - Manuscript notebook, [1917]
        In: An Exercise in analysis. A play
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Kisses can
      See: Readings
    - Kites
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, n.d.
        In: Counting
      - Typescript carbon copy (2), n.d. (Box 30, Folder 640)
    - Kristians Tonny [in English]
      - Holograph manuscript
        In: Christian Bérard (manuscript notebook)
    - Kristians Tonny [in French]
      - Holograph manuscript (2 drafts), [1929] (Box 30, Folder 641)
    - Kurmans
      See: Purmann
    - Ladies voices. A Curtain raiser
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916] (Box 31, Folder 642)
        Also contains: Every afternoon. A dialogue
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Land of nations (sub-title and ask Asia)
      - Holograph manuscript, [1920] (Box 31, Folder 643)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Land rising
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, 1920 (Box 31, Folder 644)
    - La Langue Français
      - Manuscript notebook, [1940] (Box 31, Folder 645)
      - Printed version, Patrie, 1941 AUg (Box 31, Folder 646)
    - A League
      - Holograph manuscript, [1920] (Box 31, Folder 647)
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Printed version, Life, 1919 Sep 18 (Box 31, Folder 648)
    - Lecture I[-IV]
      See: Narration
    - Lectures in America
      - What is English literature; Manuscript notebooks v. 1-5, [1934] (Box 31, Folder 649)
      - Pictures; Manuscript notebooks v. 1-4, [1934] (Box 31, Folder 650)
      - Pictures; Manuscript notebooks (3 unnumbered volumes), [1934] (Box 31, Folder 651)
      - Plays; Manuscript notebooks v. 1-3, [1934] (Box 31, Folder 652)
      - Plays; Manuscript notebook ("New Version") v. 1, [1934] (Box 31, Folder 653)
      - Plays; Manuscript notebook ("Final Version"), [1934] (Box 31, Folder 654)
      - The Gradual making of the making of the making of Americans; Manuscript notebooks v. 1-2, [1934] (Box 31, Folder 655)
        Also contains (v. 1): First page; A Plan for planting; Lucy la Fontaine; AND Or. And then silence. A Portrait of a French man
      - Portraits and repetition; Manuscript notebooks v. 1-5, [1934] (Box 31, Folder 656)
      - Poetry and grammar Manuscript notebooks v. 1-5, [1934] (Box 32, Folder 657)
      - French translation of Pictures and Poetry and Grammar by Elisabeth de Gramont, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 32, Folder 658)
      - French translation by unidentified of section of Poetry and Grammar, typescript, corrected (Box 32, Folder 659)
      - Clippings, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 660)
        See also: English literature
    - Lederman
      See: Nadelman
    - Left alone. To Basket
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
    - Left poem
      - Holograph manuscript, [1919] (Box 32, Folder 661)
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, [1919] (Box 32, Folder 662)
    - Left to right
      See: From left to right
    - Lend a hand. Four religions
      - Manuscript notebook, [1922] (Box 32, Folder 663)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Leo and Sally
      See: Two
    - A Lesson for baby
    - Let us be easily careful
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916] (Box 32, Folder 664)
        Also contains: A letter to Mr. Feneon signed Hatti Wood [1916]
      - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 32, Folder 665)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copies (2), corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 666)
    - Let us save China
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 667)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 668)
    - Let us talk about waxing
    - A Letter to Bernard Faÿ
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 669)
    - Letter to Henry McBride
      - Holograph manuscript, [ca. 1920] (Box 32, Folder 670)
      - Printed version (as "Gertrude Stein's Paris News"), [ca. 1920] (Box 32, Folder 671)
    - Letter to Pierre de Massot
      - Holograph manuscript, [1930] (Box 32, Folder 672)
    - Letter to Rousseau Voorhies
      - Printed version, Chicago Daily News, 1934 Mar 14 (Box 32, Folder 673)
    - Letter to Vanity Fair ["The native's return"]
      - Printed version, Vanity Fair, 1934 [Oct?]
    - Letters and parcels and wool
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916] (Box 32, Folder 674)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, 1916 (Box 32, Folder 675)
    - A Lide close. The story of a Spanish Morrison
      - Manuscript notebook, [1913]
        In: Mrs. Edwards
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, 1913 (Box 32, Folder 676)
    - Life and death of Juan Gris
      - Holograph manuscript, [1927] (Box 32, Folder 677)
      - Manuscript fragment, 5 May 1927
        See: Series II, General Correspondence, The Dial, Box 104, folder 2039
      - Printed version, exhibition catalog, Paris, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 678)
      - Printed version, exhibition catalog, Chicago, 1939 Jan (Box 32, Folder 679)
      - German translation (by Randolph Lerch)
        - Typescript carbon, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 680)
        - Printed version, Querschnitt, 1930 Feb (Box 32, Folder 681)
        - Printed version, Die Kinstauktion, 1930 Feb 2
        - Printed version, Exhibition catalog, Berlin, 1930 Feb (Box 32, Folder 682)
    - Lifting Belly
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1917] (Box 32, Folder 683-684)
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1917] (Box 33, Folder 685)
      - Holograph manuscript (in the hand of ABT) (Box 33, Folder 686)
      - Typescript corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, corrected, 1917 (Box 33, Folder 687)
    - Light butter
      - Manuscript notebook, [1918]
      - Typescript copy, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, 1918 (Box 33, Folder 688)
    - Like that. A comedy
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebooks, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 689)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 690)
    - Lily Life
      - Holograph manuscript, [1922] (Box 33, Folder 691)
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copies (2), corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 692)
    - Lipchitz
      - Manuscript notebook, [1925] (Box 33, Folder 693)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - A List. Inspired by Avery Hopwood
      - Holograph manuscript, [1923] (Box 33, Folder 694)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Listen to me. A play
      - Manuscript notebooks v. 1-5, [1936] (Box 33, Folder 695)
        Also contains (v. 5): Identity a poem a story and a history
      - Manuscript notebooks v. 6-7, [1936] (Box 33, Folder 696)
        Also contains (v. 6): Identity a poem a story and a history (2 versions); AND The Geographical history of America
        Also contains (v. 7): Notes for a lecture; AND Identity a poem a story and a history (another version)
      - Typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 697)
      - French translation (as Écoutez--moi une piece); Holograph manuscript, [1936] (Box 33, Folder 698)
    - Literary Notes [biographical sketch of GS]
      - Proof version, ca. 1923 (Box 33, Folder 699)
    - A Little
      - Manuscript notebook
        In: Elected Again
      - Typescript (2 copies), n.d. (Box 33, Folder 700)
    - A Little cream
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copies (3), corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 701)
    - A Little love of life
      - Manuscript notebook, [1932] (Box 33, Folder 702)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 703)
    - A Little novel
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 704)
    - Little Pillows
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copies (3), 1921 (Box 33, Folder 705)
    - Lockeridge
      - Manuscript notebook
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 706)
    - A Long gay book
      - Notes
        See: Making of Americans, Studies
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1909-12] (Box 33, Folder 707)
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1909-12] (Box 34, Folder 708-714)
      - Clipping, 1927 Sep 17 (Box 34, Folder 715)
    - Look and long
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 715a)
      - Manuscript notebook, [1943] (Box 34, Folder 716)
      - Manuscript notebook (another version), [1943]
        In: Realism in novels
      - Holograph manuscript (final version), [1943] (Box 34, Folder 717)
    - Look at us
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916]
        In: I must try to write the history of Belmonte
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript carbon copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 718)
    - Louis XI and Madame Giraud
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1930] (Box 34, Folder 719)
        Also contains: A Narrative (short version)
    - Love a delight
      - Manuscript notebook, [1927] (Box 35, Folder 720)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 721)
    - Love like anything
      See: Prothalamium
    - A Love poem
      - Holograph manuscript, [1931] (Box 35, Folder 722)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 723)
    - Love's Sacrifice or Snatched from Death
      [Play written at Radcliffe]
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 724)
    - Lucretia Borgia
      - Holograph manuscript, [1938] (Box 35, Folder 725)
      - Printed version, Creative Writing, 1939 Oct (Box 35, Folder 726)
    - Lucy Church amiably
      - Carnets with notes
        - Notes for LCA; draft of letter: to Jean Cocteau; notes between GS and ABT ["Ir#Re#Sis#Ti#Belle."]; sketch; lists of books (Box 35, Folder 727)
        - Notes for LCA [text and advertisement]; notes between GS and ABT (Box 35, Folder 728)
        - Notes for LCA: drafts of letters: to Leonard Woolf, and to Bryher and Kenneth Macpherson; notes between GS and ABT (Box 35, Folder 729)
        - Notes for LCA: draft of letter: to Bravig Imbs; sketches, notes, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 730)
        - Notes for LCA; draft of letter: to [unidentified], re: Alice Toklas' broken eyeglasses; notes between GS and ABT (Box 35, Folder 731)
        - Notes for LCA; notes between GS and ABT (Box 35, Folder 732)
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1927] (Box 35, Folder 733-735)
        Also contains (in volume 1): holograph draft of Advertisement, proof through p. 14, four-leaf clover, and notice for book - in volume 1
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1927] (Box 36, Folder 736-738)
      - Holograph Drafts of title page of Plain Edition, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 739)
      - Advertisment and subscription form, [1930] (Box 36, Folder 740)
      - Clippings, 1931-33 (Box 36, Folder 741-742)
        See also: Oversize, Box 168, folder 4313
    - Lucy La Fontaine
      - Manuscript notebook, [1934]
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 743)
    - Lynn and the College de France
      - Manuscript notebook, [1931] (Box 36, Folder 744)
    - Lyon Broadcast
      See: Broadcast at Lyon
    - A Lyrical Opera
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1928] (Box 36, Folder 745)
    - Mabel little Mabel with her face against the pane
      See: Portrait of Mabel Dodge at Villa Curonia
    - Madame de Clermont-Tonnerre
      - Manuscript notebook, [1930] (Box 36, Folder 746)
    - Madame Langlois
      - Manuscript notebook, [1929]
    - Madame Pierlot
      - Manuscript notebook, [1937]
        In: Daniel Webster. A play
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 747)
    - Madame Recamier, an operatic drama
      - Manuscript notebook, [1930] (Box 36, Folder 748)
    - Made a mile away
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1924] (Box 36, Folder 749)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 750)
    - The Making of Americans
      - Studies (numbered, assigned)
        - 1 sheet graph paper, "It has always seemed..." [#67], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 751)
        - Notebook, "I was ever of opinion..." [#33], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 752)
        - Notebook, "Some of the fathers..." [#110], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 753)
        - Typescript pages, "Begin again now with the married life...," #111, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 754)
        - Notebook, "II. Life of Dehnings and later life of Herlands" (Box 37, Folder 755)
        - Notebook, "I. When he first went East", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 756)
        - Notebook, "Felix Vallotton", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 757)
        - Holograph leaf, "David don't meet Julia..." [#51], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 758)
        - Notebook, "Hate to see you repeating yourself...", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 759)
        - Notebook, "Important for later life...", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 760)
        - Notebook, "Diagram book", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 761)
        - Holograph leaf, "Injury Free soul..." [#51], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 762)
        - 3 holograph leaves, "Pach - Singer - Francis - Derain..." [#41], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 763)
        - 8 holograph leaves, "Chalfin I am quite sure..." [#45], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 764)
        - 1 holograph leaf, [Chalfin, Leon, Putnam, etc. in diagram, #108] (Box 37, Folder 765)
        - 1 holograph leaf, [Matisse, me, Pablo, etc. in diagram, #107] (Box 37, Folder 766)
        - 12 holograph leaves, "idol with the feet of clay..." [#46], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 767)
        - 7 holograph leaves, "Harriet and the person I knew..." [#1] (Box 37, Folder 768)
        - 6 holograph leaves, "The thing that we must keep in mind..." [#42] (Box 37, Folder 769)
        - 4 holograph leaves, "In the case of Harriet..." [#43?], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 770)
        - 6 holograph leaves, "Final Statement. I am very far from certain..." [#44], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 771)
        - Holograph leaf, "Alice = pride" {#65], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 772)
        - Notebook, "Glover Memoirs" [#24], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 773)
        - Notebook, "C An important feeling...", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 774)
        - Holograph leaf, "Perhaps one of young David's..." [#169], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 775)
        - Holograph leaf, "Fernande." [#68] (Box 37, Folder 776)
        - Holograph leaf, "When it comes to description of Dehning..." [#105], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 777)
        - Notebook, "send November number of American..." [#19] (Box 37, Folder 778)
        - 12 holograph leaves, "Alfred Herland marries Bird..." [#s 88, 93, 89, 90, 92, 87, 98, 96, 97, 91] (Box 37, Folder 778a)
        - Notebook, "B I have in truth some penetration...", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 779)
        - 9 holograph leaves, "In this book give all the fashions..." [#s 34, 23, 24, 32, 14, 16, 39, 40], n.d. (Box 37, Folder 780)
        - Notebook, "Dehning's and Alfred's marriage troubles..." [#12] (Box 37, Folder 781)
        - Holograph leaf, "Then describe Herland's wife..." [#62] (Box 37, Folder 782)
        - Notebook, "Herland (old man) died..." (Box 38, Folder 783)
        - Notebook, "Fenem [?] tabby cat..." [#8], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 784)
        - Notebook, "J Simon's group are not superior...", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 785)
        - Holograph leaf, "go on to the servants..." [#78], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 786)
        - Notebook, "Blanche de Beaulieu" [on bottom of first page, #7], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 787)
        - Notebook, "A Emile About had been living a long time...", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 788)
        - Holograph leaf, "I need not be in a hurry..." [#6], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 789)
        - Notebook, "B This book follows the black note book marked A", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 790)
        - Notebook, "C This book follows the red note book marked B", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 791)
        - Notebook, "tangle Let apply[?] as Hersland's friends..." [#10] (Box 38, Folder 792)
        - 12 holograph leaves, "Loyal Go on to describe Herland's relation..." [#s 79, 81, 82, 83, 84, 84a, 86] (Box 38, Folder 793)
        - Holograph leaf, "Madaleine Weimar" [#61], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 794)
        - Notebook, "Mrs. Herland was never important..." [#5] (Box 38, Folder 795)
        - Notebook, "Refer to after dog-eared page for Martha", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 796)
        - Notebook, "I. green one follows red yellow ones" [on back], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 797)
        - Notebook, "E II green one", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 798)
        - Notebook, "F III green one.", n.d. (Box 38, Folder 799)
        - 2 holograph leaves, "Give the boy story..." [#100], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 800)
        - 2 holograph leaves, "After the introduction..." [#20], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 801)
        - Holograph leaf, "Difficulty of knowing..." [#72], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 802)
        - Notebook, "N.B. Important 21 Ave Valette Introduction to D. Herland in this book" [#3] (Box 38, Folder 803)
        - Notebook with holograph leaf laid in, "In this book, Sally, Bird and Martha Dehning..." [#s 73, 76, 76a, 77, 99] (Box 38, Folder 804)
        - Holograph leaf, "(Go onto the bottom nature..." [#74], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 805)
        - Notebook, "Who is it who without..." [at top of first page, #4], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 806)
        - Notebook, "The joy of when you are..." [#112], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 807)
        - Holograph leaf, "Begin with repetition about..." [#131], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 808)
        - Notebook, "G Red one big No I", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 809)
        - Holograph leaf, "Alfred anger..." [#129], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 810)
        - Notebook, "H Little blue one No I", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 811)
        - Notebook, "I Little green one No 6", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 812)
        - Notebook, "Alice Russell Frost Matisse" [#13], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 813)
        - Notebook, "M Big white yellow one no. I", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 814)
        - Notebook "N Eyes turn in...", n.d. (Box 39, Folder 815)
        - 7 holograph leaves, "I am content!" [#s 3, 22, 11, 10, 15, 18, 12], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 816)
        - 5 holograph leaves, "After making him noble..." [#s 29, 30, 28, 25, 26], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 817)
        - 18 holograph leaves, "In printing long book..." [#s 55, 122, 124, 106, 128, 103, 103a, 104], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 818)
        - 6 holograph leaves, "Beginning of end of long book." [#s 54, 53, 126, 31, 17] (Box 39, Folder 819)
      - Studies (numbered, unassigned)
        - 10 holograph leaves [#s 4, 5, 7, 9, 13], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 820)
        - 7 holograph leaves [#s 27, 35, 36, 37, 38], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 821)
        - 10 holograph leaves [#s 48, 49, 50, 52, 56, 58, 59, 60], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 822)
        - 4 holograph fragments [#s 63, 70, 71, 80], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 823)
        - 8 holograph leaves [# 94], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 824)
        - 8 holograph leaves [#s 101, 102, 115, 116, 117, 118, 120], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 825)
        - 5 holograph leaves [#s 121, 123, 125, 127, 130], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 826)
        - 5 holograph leaves [#s 158, 159, 162, 164, 167], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 827)
        - 45 holograph leaves and one notebook [#s 170-198] (Box 39, Folder 828)
      - Studies (unnumbered, unassigned)
        - Miscellaneous holograph pages and notebooks (Box 39, Folder 829-833)
      - First version, Manuscript notebook, ca. 1903 (Box 40, Folder 834)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 40, Folder 835-842)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 41, Folder 843-849)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 42, Folder 850-855)
        [notebook in folder 854 titled "Fernhurst" - early novel incorporated into The Making of Americans]
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 43, Folder 856-860)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 44, Folder 861-867)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 45, Folder 868-873)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 46, Folder 874-877)
      - First holograph draft, [1906-1908] (Box 47, Folder 878-886)
      - Final holograph manuscript, [1906-08] (Box 48, Folder 887-894)
      - Final holograph manuscript, [1906-08] (Box 49, Folder 895-902)
      - Final holograph manuscript, [1906-08] (Box 50, Folder 903-909)
      - Final holograph manuscript, [1906-08] (Box 51, Folder 910-914)
      - Typescript [incomplete], n.d. (Box 51, Folder 915-917)
      - Typescript [incomplete], n.d. (Box 52, Folder 918-920)
      - Critical notes in unidentified hand (Box 52, Folder 921)
      - Subscription forms, [1925] (Box 52, Folder 922)
      - French translation (done with George Hugnet) as "La Fabrication des Americains"
        - Holograph manuscript (part), [1928-29] (Box 52, Folder 923)
        - Advertisement, 1930 (Box 52, Folder 924)
      - Clippings, 1926-34 (Box 52, Folder 925-931)
        See also: Oversize, Box 168, folder 4314
    - Making of an old Maid
      See: A Kind of Women
    - Making Sense
    - Mallorcan stories
      - Manuscript notebook, [1916]
        In: Universe or hand-reading
      - Typescript, n.d.
    - A Man
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1908-12] (Box 53, Folder 932)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy (with carbon), corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 933)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 934)
      - Typescript copy (fragment), n.d. (Box 53, Folder 935)
    - Man Ray
      - Notes
      - Manuscript notebook, [1924] (Box 53, Folder 936)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, 1924 (Box 53, Folder 937)
    - Manguin
    - A Manoir...
      [Full title: A Manoir an historical play in which they are approached more often]
      - Manuscript notebook, [1932] (Box 53, Folder 938)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 939)
    - Many many women
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1910] (Box 53, Folder 940-943)
      - Manuscript notebooks, [1910] (Box 54, Folder 944)
    - Margite Marguerite and Margherita
      - Manuscript notebook (Box 54, Folder 945)
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 946)
    - Marguerite a simple novel of high life
      - Manuscript notebook, [1932] (Box 54, Folder 947)
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 948)
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 949)
    - Mark Twain Centenary
      - Holograph manuscript, [1935] (Box 54, Folder 950)
      - Typescript copy, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 951)
    - Marry Nettie...
      [Full title: Marry Nettie. Alright make it a series and call it Marry Nettie]
      - Manuscript notebook, [1917] (Box 54, Folder 952)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - Typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 953)
    - Marsden Hartley and so forth
      - Manuscript notebook, [1913] (Box 54, Folder 954)
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Printed version, exhibition catalog, New York, 1914 (Box 54, Folder 955)
    - Mary
      - Manuscript notebook, [1921]
      - Typescript, n.d.
    - Matisse
      - Holograph manuscript, [1909] (Box 54, Folder 956)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - Matisse, Storyette of
      See: Storyette of H. M.
    - Max Jacob